James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Canada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970

james-priest@outlook.com • linkedin.com/in/jamespriestdeveloper • github.com/james-priest

SUMMARY

Frontend TypeScript React, REST API, and Database Developer with 20 years' experience building web applications.

SKILLS

UI: Responsive UI/UX Design, WAI-ARIA Accessibility

Web: HTML5/CSS3, REST API Design

Database: SQL Server/MySQL, NoSQL MongoDB **Cloud:** AWS, Azure, Google, GitHub, GitLab, RestDB

Frontend: React, Hooks, Redux, Node.js, jQuery Lang: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, C#, SQL, RegEx Data: Stored Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Views Build: Vite, Webpack, Vercel, ESBuild, Rollup

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer II

Pasadena, CA

Everbridge

Sep 2019 - Jul 2024

- Chief Front End Engineer for Analytics, Usage Reporting, and Business Process Intelligence teams.
- Worked with Product and Finance to develop client-facing SaaS apps, dashboards, and data visualizations.
- Integrated Looker, Maps, Ant Design using TypeScript, React, AWS, MongoDB, Micro-frontend design.

Senior Web Application Developer / Technology Director

Pasadena, CA

Velodea

Apr 2006 - Mar 2017

- Served as Solutions Architect, Programming Lead, and Database Developer for digital marketing firm.
- Successfully built over 70 website solutions and marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 companies, including Shell, Qualcomm, Sprint, Maserati, Fox, Miramax, ABC, J. Walter Thompson, and Edelman.
- Designed large-scale learning management system to track and schedule education of 85,000 students.

Lead Developer, Founder

La Cañada, CA

devAware Technology Solutions

Jul 2002 - Mar 2006

- Excelled in building custom Web, Windows, and .NET application systems for various corporate clients.
- Hired by Sony to build advanced kiosk application for VIAO laptops, with successful nationwide rollout.

Lead Software Developer

Milan, Italy and Los Angeles, CA

The Velodea Group / Bleu22 Studios

Jul 2000 - Jul 2002

- Led the product development team of multi-national digital start-up in Milan and Los Angeles.
- Developed real-time web analytics platform to provide behavioral tracking and custom reporting.

Release Program Manager

Redmond, WA

Microsoft

Nov 1998 – Jun 2000

- Designed mission-critical app suite to manage thousands of software releases to the web each month.
- Engineered tracking and query system to manage media shipments of software to third-party vendors.

CERTIFICATIONS

React Nanodegree (React, Redux, React Native), Udacity	6-month term	June 2019
Google Mobile Web Specialist Nanodegree, Udacity	6-month term	October 2018
JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, FCC	300 hours	December 2017
Responsive Web Design, FCC	300 hours	July 2017

EDUCATION

DeVry University Pomona, CA

James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Canada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970

james-priest@outlook.com • linkedin.com/in/jamespriestdeveloper • github.com/james-priest

RECENT PROJECTS

Mobile Flashcards - App June 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2KqJE3i Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2lrc8aY



React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Redux Thunk, Expo, Animations, Notifications

Would You Rather - Game April 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2MVL2Ng Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2RkLflc



React, Redux, React Router, Redux Thunk, Auth, REST API, RestDB, Semantic-UI-React

CSS Grid Learning - App June 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2WR0Gcz Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2KpZ3AB



JavaScript ES6, CSS3 Animations, RegEx, Advanced DOM Manipulation

Triathlon Fitness Tracker - App May 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2MTVhSc Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2FhBE06



React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Geolocation, Notifications, Expo

Restaurant Reviews - App December 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2x1xwwL Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2KYE0EJ



PWA, IndexedDB, Cache API, Promise API, Service Worker, REST API, RestDB

Weather Forecast - App March 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2IphkM8 Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2MRbgQP



HTML5, Geolocation API, Semantic UI, CSS3 Animations, Async Web API